How should we work with these outliers in practice?
كيف يجب علينا العمل مع هذه القيم المتطرفة بشكل عملي؟
At the very least,
على أقل تقدير،
we should note that they exist.
يجب أن نلاحظ أنها موجودة.
We need to realize the impact they have on our summary statistics.
نحتاج إلى معرفة تأثيرها على إحصائيات الملخص.
In this case, greatly increasing our mean and our standard deviation.
في هذه الحالة، زيادة كبيرة في المتوسط والانحراف المعياري.
If the outliers are typos or data entry errors,
إذا كانت القيم المتطرفة عبارة عن أخطاء إملائية أو أخطاء في إدخال البيانات،
this is a reason to remove these points.
فهذا سبب كافٍ لإزالة هذه النقاط.
Or if we know what they should be,
أو إذا كنا نعرف ما ينبغي أن تكون،
we could change them with the correct values.
فيمكننا تغييرها بالقيم الصحيحة.
In cases like the example above,
في حالات مثل المثال أعلاه،
we might try to understand,
قد نحاول أن نفهم،
what was so different about the outlier when compared to the other individuals?
ما كان مختلفًا للغاية عن قيمة متطرفة بالمقارنة مع أفراد آخرين؟
How did this entrepreneur become so successful?
كيف أصبح هذا المستثمر ناجحًا للغاية؟
And why are the earnings so large in comparison?
ولماذا تكون الأرباح كبيرة بالمقارنة؟
There is an entire field aimed at this idea called the anomaly detection.
هناك حقل كامل يهدف إلى هذه الفكرة يسمى الكشف عن الشذوذ.
You will notice measures associated with the five number summary, like the minimum,
ستلاحظ أن الإجراءات المرتبطة بملخص العدد خمسة، مثل الحد الأدنى،
the maximum and the quartiles one, two,
والحد الأقصى، والأرباع واحد واثنين
three, are more informative when outliers are present.
وثلاثة تكون أكثر إفادة عند وجود القيم المتطرفة.
This example shows that you need to be careful about how we share our results and
يوضح هذا المثال أنك تحتاج إلى توخي الحذر بشأن كيفية مشاركة نتائجنا
state our conclusions using summary statistics when we have outliers.
وتحديد النتائج التي توصلنا إليها باستخدام إحصائيات الملخص عند وجود قيم متطرفة.
A single number can be very misleading about what is actually happening in our data.
يمكن أن يكون الرقم الواحد مضللًا للغاية حول ما يحدث بالفعل في بياناتنا.
Some statistics are more misleading than others.
تكون بعض الإحصاءات أكثر تضليلًا من غيرها.
If you are the consumer of information based on data,
إذا كنت مستهلكًا للمعلومات استنادًا إلى البيانات،
which we all are,
والتي نستهلكها جميعًا،
it's important to know how to ask
فمن المهم معرفة كيفية طرح
the right questions regarding the statistics around you.
الأسئلة الصحيحة المتعلقة بالإحصاءات من حولك.